Guide to the Charles Davis Jameson Papers, Photographs and Photograph Albums, 1887-1919 and undated RL.11422
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Charles Davis Jameson papers, photographs and photograph albums
1887-1919 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Jameson, Charles Davis, 1855-1927
RL.11422
7.3 Linear Feet
Charles Davis Jameson was an American civil engineer who lived and worked on railroads in China with the Perkin Syndicate between 1895-1918. The papers include two letters Jameson wrote to his mother; four diaries, one of which was unused; a 60-page commonplace book mainly filled with handwritten copies of published poetry, and four Japanese lithotints. The rest of the papers comprise eight typescript or published engineering reports authored by Jameson and others on Chinese projects, in English and a few in Chinese, along with two versions of Jameson's typescript description of a trip to Shanxi and Hunan. There are seventeen photograph albums, dated 1898 and undated, featuring 1255 black-and-white photographs ranging in size from 2.25 to 5.75 inches. There are also 5 loose photographs, four black-and-white, and one tinted, ranging in size from 8 x 4.5 inches to 11.5 x 9.5 inches. An additional five black-and-white photographs feature a Chinese man as an archer, holding a stone, and a wielding a kwan dao. These photographs are generally 6 x 8.25 inches and are mounted on 10 x 12.25-inch card stock.
Arrangement
Organized into the following series: Papers, Photograph albums, and Loose photographs.
Biographical / Historical
Charles Davis Jameson was an American civil engineer who lived and worked on railroads in China with the Perkin Syndicate between 1895-1918. He was the son of Gen. Charles Davis Jameson and Julia A. L. Smith. He graduated in 1876 from Bowdoin College and married Florence Miller on 1886 June 23. The couple had one son.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Charles Davis Jameson Papers, Photographs and Photograph Albums were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a purchase in 2016.
Related Materials
William Hillman Shockley photographs, Sidney D. Gamble photographs, Lucy Monroe Calhoun family photographs and papers
Collection Overview
The papers include two letters Jameson wrote to his mother; four diaries, one of which was unused; a 60-page commonplace book mainly filled with handwritten copies of published poetry, and four Japanese lithotints. The rest of the papers comprise eight typescript or published engineering reports authored by Jameson and others on Chinese projects, in English and a few in Chinese, along with two versions of Jameson's typescript description of a trip to Shanxi and Hunan.
There are also seventeen photograph albums, dated 1898 and undated, featuring 1255 black-and-white photographs ranging in size from 2.25 to 5.75 inches. There are albumen and gelatin silver prints. One of the albums is a commercial Japanese album that features hand-tinted photographs. Two albums focus on Shanxi province; three others focus on Beijing. Subjects include waterways and boats, landscapes, groups of Chinese or Westerners, engineering projects, street scenes, rural life, caravans, portraits, missionaries, houses for Westerners, farming and rice crops, and temples and other buildings. Five photographs in photograph album 2 are duplicates of photographs in the William Hillman Shockley photographs collection.
There are 5 loose photographs, four black-and-white, and one tinted, ranging in size from 8 x 4.5 inches to 11.5 x 9.5 inches. Three photographs of international locations, including Fingall's Cave, Scotland; a temple in Agra, India, and a scene of Geneva, Switzerland, are all mounted. The subjects of the other two photographs are a Chinese waterway with three boats, and a courtyard with a Western man being waited on by a Chinese servant. An additional five black-and-white photographs feature a Chinese man as an archer, holding a stone, and a wielding a kwan dao. These photographs are generally 6 x 8.25 inches and are mounted on 10 x 12.25-inch card stock.
Civil engineers -- China; Documentary Photography -- China; Engineering -- Research -- China; Photography -- China; Fingal's Cave (Scotland) -- Photographs; Agra (India) -- Pictorial works; Geneva (Switzerland) -- Photographs; Beijing (China) -- Pictorial works; China -- History -- 1861-1912; China -- Photographs; China -- Pictorial works; China -- Social life and customs -- 1644-1912; Hunan Sheng (China); Shanxi Sheng (China); Shanxi Sheng (China) -- Photographs; Black-and-white photographs; Tinting.; Photograph albums; Albumen prints; Gelatin silver prints; Diaries; Commonplace books; Lithotints; Administrative reports; Typescripts; Jameson, Charles Davis, 1855-1927; Shockley, W. H., 1855-1925
- Papers
  Scope and Contents
  The papers series includes two letters Jameson wrote to his mother; four diaries, one of which was unused; a 60-page commonplace book mainly filled with handwritten copies of published poetry, and four Japanese lithotints. The rest of the series comprises eight typescript or published engineering reports authored by Jameson and others on Chinese projects, in English and a few in Chinese, along with two versions of Jameson's typescript description of a trip to Shansi and Hunan.
  - Letters, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Two handwritten letters from Jameson to his mother, 2 pages and 8 pages, dated 1911 November 8 and 13.
  - Diary, 1903 (Box 2)
    Commercial diary filled with notes on Jameson's work and travel. Semi-regular entries July through December.
  - Diary, 1906 (Box 2)
    Commercial diary filled with Jameson's notes on his work, pastimes, travel, and the people he meets. Almost daily entries, except for the months of March and April.
  - Diary, 1910 (Box 2)
    Commercial diary with only scattered entries until August, when regular entries begin. Includes entries for 1-6 January 1911. Jamesoon was based in the United States during this year, and records his activities, visitors and visiting.
  - Diary, 1917 (Box 2)
    Commercial diary, void of entries.
  - Commonplace book, undated (Box 3)
    Contains a 60-page commonplace book filled with published poetry and verse.
  - Lithotints, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Includes four Japanese lithotints, sized 11.5 x 9.25, showing Japanese homes; a religious shrine; and two figures walking on a beach near a volcano, possibly Mt. Fuji.
  - Railroad and Engineering Journal: Principles of Railway Location, 1887 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Contains published articles by Jameson on this subject.
  - Railroad and Engineering Journal: The Use of Wood in Railway Structures, 1889 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Notes: Shansi and Hunan (incomplete), 1897 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Contains a 37-page incomplete typescript, a. Accompanied by a map.
  - Notes in Shansi and Hunan China, 1897 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Contains an approximately 119-page typescript by Jameson.
  - Chinese Coal Mines reports, 1904 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Contains typescript reports on the Lin Tcheng Coal Mines (4 pages plus two pages maps) and the Coal basin of the Tse Chow, South Chili (8 pages).
  - American Red Cross Report on Huai River Conservancy, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Contains a published 28-page report, with two maps, along with a seoarate Chinese translation.
  - Report on Reconnoissance....., 1917 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Contains 43-page typescript report on reconnoissance from Hsiangyangfu, Hupeh to Hinganfu, Shensi. There are also maps, and 71 black-and-white photographs of the trip.
  - North River System, 1919 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Contains a 70-page published report, with extra charts and maps.
  - Evolution of China and Japan (incomplete), undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Contains a 13-page incomplete typescript.
  - Jiang Huai Water Conservatory Regulations, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Contains a 120-page report in Chinese.
- Photograph albums
  Seventeen photograph albums, dated 1898 and undated, featuring 1255 black-and-white photographs ranging in size from 2.25 to 5.75 inches. One of the albums is a commercial Japanese album, and features hand-tinted photographs. Two albums focus on Shanxi province; three others focus on Beijing. Subjects include waterways and boats, landscapes, groups of Chinese or Westerners, engineering projects, street scenes, rural life, caravans, portraits, missionaries, houses for Westerners, farming and rice crops, and temples and other buildings. Five photographs in photograph album 2 are duplicates of photographs in the William Hillman Shockley photographs collection.
  - Photograph album 1, 1890s
    - Paifang at Bi Yun Si (should be Yellow Temple (Xi Huang Si)), 1890s; 6 x 4 in. (Box 6, Album 1, Print RL11422-P-0001)
      Title (Chinese)
      碧云寺牌坊（应为西黄寺"慧因寰上"牌坊)
      Mount caption
      Pi Yuen Ssu
      Description
      Page 1. Location should be the Paifang at Xi Huang Si, misattributed in the original caption.
    - Courtyard at Bi Yun Si, 1890s; 6 x 4 in. (Box 6, Album 1, Print RL11422-P-0002)
      碧云寺院落
      Page 2.
    - Wall and Halls at Bi Yun Si, 1890s; 6 x 4.25 in. (Box 6, Album 1, Print RL11422-P-0003)
      碧云寺院墙和建筑
      Page 3.
    - Courtyard with plantings at Bi Yun Si, 1890s; 6 x 4.25 in. (Box 6, Album 1, Print RL11422-P-0004)
      碧云寺院中盆栽
      Page 4.
    - Hall at Wo Fo Si, 1890s; 6 x 4.25 in. (Box 6, Album 1, Print RL11422-P-0005)
      卧佛寺一殿堂
      Wu fu Ssu
      Page 5.
    - Standing bodhisattva at Bi Yun Si, 1890s; 4.25 x 5.75 in. (Box 6, Album 1, Print RL11422-P-0006)
      碧云寺菩萨立像
      Page 6.
    - Pifang at Bi Yun Si, 1890s; 6 x 4 in. (Box 6, Album 1, Print RL11422-P-0007)
      碧云寺牌坊
      Page 7.
    - Soul Tower at Ming tombs, 1890s; 4 x 5.5 in. (Box 6, Album 1, Print RL11422-P-0008)
      明陵明楼
      Page 8.
    - Entrance to Wo Fo Si, 1890s; 6 x 4 in. (Box 6, Album 1, Print RL11422-P-0009)
      卧佛寺入口
      Page 9. Location should be Ming tombs, misattributed in the original caption.
    - Wo Fo Si Sleeping Buddha, 1890s; 6 x 4.25 in. (Box 6, Album 1, Print RL11422-P-0010)
      卧佛寺的卧佛
      Wu fu Ssu Sleeping Buddha 18' long
      Page 10.
    - Silk Burning Furnace at Ming tombs, 1890s; 6 x 4 in. (Box 6, Album 1, Print RL11422-P-0011)
      明陵焚帛炉
      Page 11. Location should be Ming tombs, misattributed in the original caption.
    - Temple Hall at Wo Fo Si, 1890s; 6 x 4.25 in. (Box 6, Album 1, Print RL11422-P-0012)
      卧佛寺的一个佛堂大门
      Page 12.
    - House on road to Nan Kou, 1890s; 5.75 x 4.25 in. (Box 6, Album 1, Print RL11422-P-0013)
      通向南口的道路
      Road to Nan Kou
      Page 13.
    - Phoebe zhennan wood pillars at Ming Changling Tomb's Eminent Favor Hall, 1890s; 6 x 4.25 in. (Box 6, Album 1, Print RL11422-P-0014)
      明长陵祾恩殿内的金丝楠木大柱子
      [no caption present]
      Page 14.
    - Temple buildings on road to Nan Kou, 1890s; 6 x 4.25 in. (Box 6, Album 1, Print RL11422-P-0015)
      通向南口的道路两边山坡上的佛寺建筑
      Page 15.
    - Temple Buildings (close-up) on road to Nan Kou, 1890s; 6 x 4.25 in. (Box 6, Album 1, Print RL11422-P-0016)
      通向南口的道路两边山坡上的佛寺近景
      Page 16.
    - Road beyond Nan Kou, 1890s; 6 x 4 in. (Box 6, Album 1, Print RL11422-P-0017)
      南口入关后的道路
      Road beyond Nan Kou
      Page 17.
    - Great Wall, Nan Kou, 1890s; 6 x 4 in. (Box 6, Album 1, Print RL11422-P-0018)
      南口处的长城
      Great Wall, Nan Kou
      Page 18.
    - Great Wall with Mountains at Nan Kou, 1890s; 6 x 4.25 in. (Box 6, Album 1, Print RL11422-P-0019)
      南口处山上的长城
      Page 19.
    - Ming Tombs Paifang, 1890s; 6 x 4.25 in. (Box 6, Album 1, Print RL11422-P-0020)
      明十三陵的石牌坊
      Ming Tombs
      Page 20.
    - Merit and Virtue Pavilion at Ming Tombs, 1890s; 5.75 x 4.25 in. (Box 6, Album 1, Print RL11422-P-0021)
      明十三陵神功圣德碑亭
      Page 21.
    - Yellow Temple (Xi Huang Si) Paifang & Courtyard, 1890s; 4.25 x 5.5 in. (Box 6, Album 1, Print RL11422-P-0022)
      西黄寺牌坊及院落
      Yellow Temple
      Page 22.
    - Yellow Temple (Xi Huang Si) Paifang, 1890s; 6 x 4.25 in. (Box 6, Album 1, Print RL11422-P-0023)
      西黄寺"慧因寰上"牌坊
      Page 23.
    - U.S.S. Monocacy --Tanggu 1896-97, 1896-1897; 6 x 4.25 in. (Box 6, Album 1, Print RL11422-P-0024)
      美国明轮炮舰"莫诺卡西"号-- 塘沽, 1898-1897年
      U.S.S. Monocacy --Tangku 1896-97
      Page 24.
    - Chinese woman seated next to side table holding a clock, teapot, teacup, and water tobacco pipe, 1890s; 4.25 x 6 in. (Box 6, Album 1, Print RL11422-P-0025)
      妇女坐在小桌边，桌上有钟表、茶壶、茶碗和水烟袋
      Type
      Page 25.
    - Male Chinese Christian, 1890s; 4 x 4.75 in. (Box 6, Album 1, Print RL11422-P-0026)
      男性基督教信徒
      Chinese Christian
      Page 26.
    - Chinese Priest, 1890s; 4.25 x 6 in. (Box 6, Album 1, Print RL11422-P-0027)
      佛教僧人
      Chinese Priest
      Page 27.
    - Chinese man holding smoking pipe, seated next to side table with flower vase and teapot, 1890s; 4.25 x 5.75 in. (Box 6, Album 1, Print RL11422-P-0028)
      男子手持水烟袋坐在桌边，桌上有插花和茶壶
      Our Earnest Inquirer
      Page 28.
    - Friends with family, 1890s; 6 x 4.25 in. (Box 6, Album 1, Print RL11422-P-0029)
      合影，旁边题字：X(杨?暢?)園幕遊湘南 燕北石X(谏?谅?)時官水部 天涯團聚 其樂何如 行將分襼 籍自圖中見真面耳
      Chinese family
      Page 29.
    - Male Chinese laborer, with braided and coiled hair., 1890s; 4 x 5.75 in. (Box 6, Album 1, Print RL11422-P-0030)
      苦力，辫子盘在头上
      Coolie
      Page 30.
    - Beggars eating -- Tientsin, 1890s; 3.5 x 3.75 in. (Box 6, Album 1, Print RL11422-P-0031)
      吃饭的两个小乞丐，天津
      Beggars -- Tientsin
      Page 32.
    - Male Chinese Christian with moustache and beard, 1890s; 2.75 x 3.75 in. (Box 6, Album 1, Print RL11422-P-0032)
      蓄须的男性基督教信徒
    - Chinese man, seated, 1890s; 2.75 x 3.75 in. (Box 6, Album 1, Print RL11422-P-0033)
      男子坐像
      Page 33.
    - Gold miners-- northern Mongolia, 1895, 4.5 x 3.75 in. (Box 6, Album 1, Print RL11422-P-0034)
      金矿上的工人，北蒙古，1895年
      Gold miners northern Mongolia 1895
    - Chinese Inn -- Mongolia, 1890s; 4.75 x 3.75 in. (Box 6, Album 1, Print RL11422-P-0035)
      客店，蒙古
      Chinese Inn Mongolia
      Page 34.
    - K. Kurulff's Back Yard -- Tientsin, 1890s; 5.75 x 3.5 in. (Box 6, Album 1, Print RL11422-P-0036)
      库洛夫的后院 -- 天津
      K. Kurulff's Back Yard -- Tientsin
      Page 35.
    - Charles Davis Jameson dressed for Mongolia, 1890s; 4 x 5.75 in. (Box 6, Album 1, Print RL11422-P-0037)
      詹美生穿着蒙古传统服装
      C.D.J. -- 1895 -- for Mongolia
      Page 36.
    - Wutai Mountain -- Central Tai -- Grand Dagoba Dec. 1897, 3 x 4 in. (Box 6, Album 1, Print RL11422-P-0038)
      五台山 -- 中台 -- 大白塔（舍利塔）1897年12月
      Wu Tai Shan -- Central Tai -- Grand Dagoba Dec. 1897
      Page 37.
    - The brick Amitaba Hall (also called Beamless Hall) of the Xiantong Temple, Wutai Mountain, Dec. 1897, 3 x 4 in. (Box 6, Album 1, Print RL11422-P-0039)
      显通寺无量殿(又称无梁殿)，五台山，1897年12月
      Main Temple Dec. 1897
    - A Hall at Yuan Zhao Si, 1890s; 3 x 4 in. (Box 6, Album 1, Print RL11422-P-0040)
      圆照寺大殿
      Court
      Page 38.
    - Mongol Priests, 1890s; 4 x 3 in. (Box 6, Album 1, Print RL11422-P-0041)
      蒙古僧侣
      Mongol Priests
    - Temple Court; Mongol Temple at top, 1890s; 3 x 4 in. (Box 6, Album 1, Print RL11422-P-0042)
      寺院; 山顶的蒙古寺院
      Temple Court Mongol Temple at top
      Page 39.
    - Mongol Temple at top, 1890s; 3 x 4 in. (Box 6, Album 1, Print RL11422-P-0043)
      山顶的蒙古寺院
      Mongol Temple at top
    - Wutai Mountain -- Central Tai -- Grand Dagoba, 1890s; 2.875 x 4 in. (Box 6, Album 1, Print RL11422-P-0044)
      五台山 -- 中台 -- 大白塔（舍利塔）
      Dagoba
      Page 40.
    - One of the Five Copper Pagodas at Xian Tong Si, 1890s; 3 x 4 in. (Box 6, Album 1, Print RL11422-P-0045)
      显通寺无座铜塔中的一座
      Small Tai
    - One of the Five Copper Pagodas at Xian Tong Si, 1890s; 3 x 4 in. (Box 6, Album 1, Print RL11422-P-0046)
      Page 41.
    - One of the Five Copper Pagodas at Xian Tong Si, 1890s; 2.875 x 4 in. (Box 6, Album 1, Print RL11422-P-0047)
    - Copper Hall (close up) at Xian Tong Si, 1890s; 3 x 4 in. (Box 6, Album 1, Print RL11422-P-0048)
      显通寺铜殿（近照）
      Gilt Temple
      Page 42.
    - Copper Hall (distant) at Xian Tong Si, 1890s; 3 x 4 in. (Box 6, Album 1, Print RL11422-P-0049)
      显通寺铜殿（远照）
    - Copper Hall behind another hall at Xian Tong Si, 1890s; 2.875 x 4.25 in. (Box 6, Album 1, Print RL11422-P-0050)
      显通寺中靠后面的铜殿
      Page 43.
    - Y.M.C.A. Tianjin 1896, 3.25 x 2.875 in. (Box 6, Album 1, Print RL11422-P-0051)
      天津基督教青年会修建工地， 1896年
      Y.M.C.A. Tientsin 1896
      Page 45.
    - Y.M.C.A. under construction, man carrying things, 1896; 3.25 x 2.875 in. (Box 6, Album 1, Print RL11422-P-0052)
      天津基督教青年会修建工地, 挑着建材的工人
      Y.M.C.A.
    - Y.M.C.A. bricklayer, 1896; 3.25 x 2.875 in. (Box 6, Album 1, Print RL11422-P-0053)
      天津基督教青年会修建工地, 背砖的工人
      Page 46.
    - Carpenter Shop -- Tianjin 1896, 3.25 x 2.875 in. (Box 6, Album 1, Print RL11422-P-0054)
      木匠铺，天津，1896年
      Carpenter Shop -- Tientsin 1896
    - Wood Sawyers, 1890s; 3.25 x 3 in. (Box 6, Album 1, Print RL11422-P-0055)
      两人锯大木头
      Wood Sawyers
      Page 47.
    - Knife Sharpener, 1890s; 3.25 x 3 in. (Box 6, Album 1, Print RL11422-P-0056)
      磨刀匠
      Knife Sharpener
    - Taku Rd. -- Tianjin, 1890s; 3.5 x 3 in. (Box 6, Album 1, Print RL11422-P-0057)
      大沽路，天津，1896年
      Taku Rd. -- Tientsin
      Page 48.
    - Mrs. Blackwood -- Tianjin 1896, 3.5 x 2.875 in. (Box 6, Album 1, Print RL11422-P-0058)
      布莱克伍德夫人，天津，1896年
      Mrs. Blackwood -- Tientsin 1896
    - H. K.'s Hans 1896 --Tianjin, 3.25 x 3 in. (Box 6, Album 1, Print RL11422-P-0059)
      保姆抱着Hans，天津，1896年
      H. K.'s Hans 1896 --Tientsin
      Page 49.
    - Beggars -- Tianjin, 1890s; 3.25 x 2.875 in. (Box 6, Album 1, Print RL11422-P-0060)
      乞丐，天津
    - Naked male child near house, 1890s; 3.25 x 3 in. (Box 6, Album 1, Print RL11422-P-0061)
      屋前赤身裸体的小男孩
      Summer dress
      Page 50.
    - Naked male child carrying sticks in street, 1890s; 3.25 x 3 in. (Box 6, Album 1, Print RL11422-P-0062)
      赤身裸体的小男孩拿着一捆柴
  - Photograph album 2, 1890s
    - Chinese man with moustache, holding fan, 1890s; 4 x 5.25 in. (Box 8, Album 2, Print RL11422-P-0063)
      一名蓄须男子，手持一把折扇
      Page 1.
    - Twin pagodas at Yong Zuo Si, 1890s; 4 x 5.875 in. (Box 8, Album 2, Print RL11422-P-0064)
      永祚寺双塔
    - Nine men and one boy at a pavillion, 1890s; 4.75 x 4 in. (Box 8, Album 2, Print RL11422-P-0065)
      凉亭旁的九人和一孩童
    - Seven men holding fans, seated at the formal hall, 1890s; 5.75 x 4 in. (Box 8, Album 2, Print RL11422-P-0066)
      堂前七人手持扇子合影
    - Temple entrance and a paifang on the side, 1890s; 5.75 x 4 in. (Box 8, Album 2, Print RL11422-P-0067)
      寺院大门和一旁的牌坊
    - Man in front of Zi Zhu Lin Si, 1890s; 5.25 x 4.25 in. (Box 8, Album 2, Print RL11422-P-0068)
      一男子站在紫竹林寺前
    - Street scene with men gathering grain into sacks, 1890s; 5.875 x 3.75 in. (Box 8, Album 2, Print RL11422-P-0069)
      街道两旁人们把谷物装袋
    - Market scene, men with donkeys and horses, 1890s; 5.5 x 3.5 in. (Box 8, Album 2, Print RL11422-P-0070)
      集市上，人群和驴马
    - Looking down on building compound, 1890s; 5.25 x 4 in. (Box 8, Album 2, Print RL11422-P-0071)
      院落俯瞰
    - Chinese man holding kwan dao, 1890s; 5.875 x 4.25 in. (Box 8, Album 2, Print RL11422-P-0072)
      手持大刀的人
    - Chinese archer, standing, 1890s; 4.125 x 6 in. (Box 8, Album 2, Print RL11422-P-0073)
      张弓搭箭的人
    - Chinese archer on horseback, 1890s; 4.25 x 5.75 in. (Box 8, Album 2, Print RL11422-P-0074)
      射箭手骑在马上
    - Chinese archer on horseback, leaning forward, 1890s; 4.125 x 5.75 in. (Box 8, Album 2, Print RL11422-P-0075)
      射箭手骑在马上弯腰准备射箭
    - Chinese man with stone, 1890s; 4.125 x 5.5 in. (Box 8, Album 2, Print RL11422-P-0076)
      准备抬起大石
    - Buddha with two deities, 1890s; 5.5 x 3.875 in. (Box 8, Album 2, Print RL11422-P-0077)
      佛像及两旁的侍者像
      Page 9.
    - Multiple Buddhas, 1890s; 5.75 x 4 in. (Box 8, Album 2, Print RL11422-P-0078)
      两尊主佛像和一侧的小佛像群
    - Chinese crowd following surveyor, 1890s; 5.875 x 4.125 in. (Box 8, Album 2, Print RL11422-P-0079)
      一群人围观勘测的进行
    - Seven Chinese boys in a field, 1890s; 6 x 4.125 in. (Box 8, Album 2, Print RL11422-P-0080)
      七个小孩在田野中的合影
    - Chinese crowd beside surveyor's equipment, 1890s; 6 x 4 in. (Box 8, Album 2, Print RL11422-P-0081)
      围观勘测的人群，有人负责维持秩序
      Page 11.
    - Five Chinese men in the survey team standing on a hill, 1890s; 6 x 4.125 in. (Box 8, Album 2, Print RL11422-P-0082)
      勘测队里的几个中国人
    - Four Chinese women whose feet have been bound, at distance, 1890s; 5.875 x 4.125 in. (Box 8, Album 2, Print RL11422-P-0083)
      四个裹小脚的妇女
    - Four Chinese women whose feet have been bound, closeup, 1890s; 6 x 4 in. (Box 8, Album 2, Print RL11422-P-0084)
      四个裹小脚的妇女近照
      Page 12. Version of RL11422-P-0083
    - Charles Davis Jameson in cape on a donkey, with Chinese man, 1890s; 6 x 4.25 in. (Box 8, Album 2, Print RL11422-P-0085)
      詹美生披着斗篷骑着毛驴，旁边站着他雇用的中国人
    - Four Chinese men in the survey team, 1890s; 6 x 4.125 in. (Box 8, Album 2, Print RL11422-P-0086)
      四个勘测队的中国人
    - Women and children next to low building beside a river, 1890s; 6 x 4.125 in. (Box 8, Album 2, Print RL11422-P-0087)
      河边低矮的农舍和岸边的几个妇女和孩童
    - Chinese sailboat near riverbank, 1890s; 6 x 4.125 in. (Box 8, Album 2, Print RL11422-P-0088)
      河面上扬帆的船
    - Two Chinese sailboats near riverbank with low buildings, 1890s; 6 x 4 in. (Box 8, Album 2, Print RL11422-P-0089)
      河面上的两艘帆船和岸边低矮的房屋
    - Two people, a woman seated, a man standing, at the courtyard of a Chinese house, 1890s; 5.5 x 4 in. (Box 8, Album 2, Print RL11422-P-0090)
      庭院中一位妇女坐在竹椅上，一男子站在柱子旁
    - Two carts pulled up to a house with a group of Chinese Christians on the porch, 1890s; 5.75 x 4.125 in. (Box 8, Album 2, Print RL11422-P-0091)
      一辆牛车和一辆马车，房前的一群中国教徒
    - Group of Chinese with one Westerner gathered at a porch, 1890s; 5.75 x 4 in. (Box 8, Album 2, Print RL11422-P-0092)
      一群中国人和人群中的一个西方人
    - Charles Davis Jameson(?) sitting on a couch with furs, 1890s; 4 x 6 in. (Box 8, Album 2, Print RL11422-P-0093)
      詹美生坐在铺着兽皮的椅子上
    - Six people, all Westerners except one Chinese man, standing on external stairway to house, 1890s; 5.5 x 4 in. (Box 8, Album 2, Print RL11422-P-0094)
      房屋一侧楼梯上站着的六个人，其中一个是中国人，其余为外国人
    - Group of ten Chinese, some sitting, some standing, 1890s; 5.5 x 4 in. (Box 8, Album 2, Print RL11422-P-0095)
      十人合影
    - Loaded cart with two female Westerners, one Chinese man, 1890s; 5.75 x 4 in. (Box 8, Album 2, Print RL11422-P-0096)
      装满东西的大车上坐着两人西方妇女，一个中国人在赶车
    - Western woman and man (standing) and a Chinese woman and man (seated), posing around a table with two vases of flowers, 1890s; 5.75 x 4 in. (Box 8, Album 2, Print RL11422-P-0097)
      桌两侧坐着的中国夫妇和桌后站着的一对外国夫妇
    - Rear of Chinese house, 1890s; 6 x 4.25 in. (Box 8, Album 2, Print RL11422-P-0098)
      一个庭院的后侧面
    - The Paifang at Wenchang Temple, three Chinese men on stairs, 1890s; 5.5 x 4 in. (Box 8, Album 2, Print RL11422-P-0099)
      文昌庙的佑文广化坊，台阶上坐着三个中国人
    - Christian ceremony being held outdoors, 1890s; 5.625 x 4.125 in. (Box 8, Album 2, Print RL11422-P-0100)
      室外的天主教仪式
    - Looking down on a Catholic church, 1890s; 5.75 x 4 in. (Box 8, Album 2, Print RL11422-P-0101)
      天主教堂
    - Bell tower at a temple, 1890s; 3.125 x 4.75 in. (Box 8, Album 2, Print RL11422-P-0102)
      寺院的钟楼
    - Bridge pass, 1890s; 6 x 4 in. (Box 8, Album 2, Print RL11422-P-0103)
      石桥
    - Entrance to a mountain temple, 1890s; 5.25 x 4.25 in. (Box 8, Album 2, Print RL11422-P-0104)
      依山而建的寺庙
    - Five people at a pond in a valley, 1890s; 5.75 x 4 in. (Box 8, Album 2, Print RL11422-P-0105)
      山谷中水池边休憩的五人
    - Terraced landscape with crops, 1890s; 6 x 4 in. (Box 8, Album 2, Print RL11422-P-0106)
      层层梯田
    - Terraced landscape with crops, 1890s; 5.625 x 2.75 in. (Box 8, Album 2, Print RL11422-P-0107)